HENRY PAUL MACAFEE

MODERN WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

Address

PO Box 50963 Nashville, TN 37205

Contact

henry.macafee@gmail.com 615-939-7377



ABOUT ME

As the web has evolved over time, I have found great personal enjoyment from learning new technologies in order to streamline the development of powerful web applications. Never before have so many tools made it possible to channel my creativity into creating compelling, responsive, and inspiring user experiences.

Through my experience, both outside the development world and also with these technologies, I have become an exceptional problem solver. My determination and my ability to think creatively have been a winning combination when it has come to finding the right solution in many different contexts. I am a fast and avid learner and only feel truly fulfilled if I have the opportunity to improve my understanding or learn something new every day.

I have found that one of the most undervalued skills in the professional development world is the ability to communicate clearly. I pride myself on being able to express abstract ideas well, with respect for the specific skills and understanding my audience possesses. Given the opportunity, I guarantee that I will perform my absolute best, meeting and exceeding your expectations!



WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer/Designer

October 2002 - July 2008, August 2015 - Current

- Created and administered a forum website for my social group, with over 200 members at peak, including managing a team to assist in moderating user posts
- Began work on a startup/recommendation engine using Neo4j (graph database), Python (for working with batch scripts and basic data analysis), Javascript, Node.js, React, CSS, SASS, & HTML
- Consulted with various small business owners regarding branding, design language choices, and technology choices
- Designed posters and pamphlets for concerts, venues, and other events using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop

Private Violin Instructor

Mary's Music, Clarksville, TN, August 2012 - Current

- Maintained a vibrant teaching studio between 20-30 students of all ages and skill levels
- Coordinated with students and parents to mitigate scheduling conflicts, manage make-up lessons, and to welcome new students
- Tracked independent progress across each of my students and regularly discussed goals and expectations.

Freelance Musician

July 2006 - Current

- Contracted gigs for weddings and other special events, working with wedding coordinators, brides, and family members
- Composed arrangements for requested music, including pop music with sensitivity for context and instrumentation
- Performed at hundreds of venues performing my own original music as well as being a part of various ensembles



EDUCATION

Austin Peay State University

Clarksville, TN - Class of 2013 Master of Music - Violin Performance

Tennessee Tech University

Cookeville, TN - Class of 2011 Bachelor of Music - Composition



TECHNOLOGIES

HTML	•	O	()	O	()	()	()	•	•	0
CSS	()	O	()	()	()	•	•	•	•	0
React	O	O	O	O	O	•	()	•	0	0
Javascript	()	()	()	()	O	•	O	0	0	0
Python	()	O	O	()	O	•	0	0	0	0
Microsoft Office	()	O	O	()	O	•	O	•	•	0
Adobe Cloud	()	O	O	()	O	•	()	•	0	0
Typing (112 WPM)	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•



NOTABLE PERSONAL SKILLS

Professionalism
Organization
Creativity
Problem-Solving
Communication
Teamwork
Work Ethic



HOBBIES AND INTERESTS





Coffee



Photography



Travelling



Music



Design

Web Portfolio:

henrymacafee.netlify.com

l inkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/henry-macafee-42887743/